Welcome back. In this video, we're going to give a very brief introduction, an
欢迎回来。在这段视频中，我们将做一个非常简短的介绍，
overview, of what we're going to be talking about in semantic analysis. Let's
概述，我们将在语义分析中讨论的内容。我们走吧
take a moment to review where we are in our discussion with compilers. So we
花点时间回顾一下我们与编译器的讨论进展如何。所以我们
talked about lexical analysis, and from the point of view of enforcing the
谈到了词法分析，并从执行
language definition the main job that lexical analyses does is detect input
语言定义词法分析的主要工作是检测输入
[inaudible] preemptive symbols that aren't part of our language. The next step is
[听不见]先发制人的符号不是我们语言的一部分。下一步是
parsing. We finished talking about that too. And, again, from the point of view of
正在解析。我们也谈完了那件事。再说一遍，从
trying to determine whether a program is well-formed or not, or whether it's a
尝试确定程序是否格式良好，或者它是否是
valid program, the job of parsing is to detect all the sentences in the language
有效的程序，分析的工作是检测语言中的所有句子
that are ill-formed, or that don't have a parse string. And finally What we're going
格式错误，或者没有解析字符串。最后我们要做的是
to talk about now, what's going to occupy us for a while is semantic analysis. And
现在我们要谈的是语义分析。和
this is the last of what are called the front end phases. So if you think of
这是所谓的前端阶段中的最后一个阶段。所以如果你想到
lexical analysis, parsing, and semantic analysis as filters that progressively
作为过滤器的词法分析、解析和语义分析
reject more and more input strings until finally you're left after all three phases
拒绝越来越多的输入字符串，直到最后在所有三个阶段结束后才离开
have run with only valid programs to compile, well semantic analysis is the
已经运行过的只有有效的程序要编译，很好的语义分析是
last line of defense. It's the last one in that pipeline and its job is to catch all
最后一道防线。它是管道中的最后一个，它的工作是捕获所有
potential remaining errors in a program. Now you might ask yourself, why do we even
程序中潜在的剩余错误。现在你可能会问自己，为什么我们甚至
need a separate semantic analysis phase? And the answer to that's very simple,
需要单独的语义分析阶段吗？这个问题的答案很简单，
There are, there are some features of programming languages, some kinds of
有，有一些编程语言的一些特点，有一些
mistakes you can make that parsings simply can't catch. Parsing we'll use in context
你可以犯的错误是你根本无法捕捉到的。我们将在上下文中使用的解析
free grammars is not expressive enough to describe everything that we're interested
自由语法不足以描述我们感兴趣的一切
in, in a language definition. So, some of these language constructs are not context
在语言定义中。因此，这些语言结构中的一些不是上下文
free. And the situation here is very, very similar to what it was when we switched
免费的。这里的情况与我们切换时非常非常相似
from lexical analysis to parsing. Just like not everything could be done with a
从词法分析到句法分析。就像不是所有事情都可以用
finite [inaudible]. And we wanted to have something more. Our context free grammar
有限的[听不见的]我们想要更多的东西。我们的上下文无关文法
to describe additional features of our programming languages [inaudible] Grammars
描述我们的编程语言[听不见的]语法的附加功能
by themselves are also not enough, and there some additional features beyond
仅靠它们本身也是不够的，除此之外还有一些额外的功能
those that can't be easily expressed using context free constructs. So what does
那些不能使用上下文无关构造轻松表达的内容。那么，什么是
semantic analysis actually do? In a case of cool C, it does checks of many
语义分析真的能做到吗？在酷C的情况下，它会检查很多
different kinds, and that's pretty typical. So here's a list of six classes
不同的种类，这是相当典型的。所以这里有六个班级的清单
of checks that are done by Cool C, and let's just run through them quickly. First
由Cool C完成的检查，让我们快速浏览一下。第一
we want to check that all identifiers are declared, and we also have to check that
我们希望检查所有标识符是否都已声明，并且我们还必须检查
any scope restrictions on those identifiers are observed. Cool C compiler
将遵守对这些标识符的任何范围限制。Cool C编译器
has to do type checking, and this is actually a major function of the semantic
必须进行类型检查，这实际上是语义的一个主要功能
analyzer in Cool. There are a number of restrictions that come from the object
分析器处于冷却状态。有许多来自对象的限制
oriented nature of Cool. We have to check that the inheritance relationships between
面向酷的本质。我们必须检查它们之间的继承关系
classes make sense. We don't want classes to be redefined; we only want one class
课程是有意义的。我们不希望重新定义类；我们只需要一个类
definition per class. Similarly methods should only be defined once within a
每个类的定义。类似地，方法在
class. Cool has a number of reserved identifiers and we have to be careful that
班级。Cool有许多保留的标识符，我们必须小心
those aren't misused. And this is pretty typical; lots of languages have some
这些没有被误用。这是相当典型的；很多语言都有一些
reserved identifiers with special rules that have to be followed for those
保留标识符，具有必须遵循的特殊规则
identifiers. And, actually this list is not even complete. There are a number of
标识符。而且，实际上这份名单甚至还不完整。这里有很多
other restrictions. And we'll be talking about all of those in future videos. The
其他限制。我们将在未来的视频中讨论所有这些问题。这个
main message here is that its medic analyzer needs to do quite a few different
这里的主要信息是它的医疗分析器需要做很多不同的事情
kinds of checks. These checks will vary with the language. The kinds of checks
各种支票。这些检查将随语言的不同而不同。支票的种类
that cool C does are pretty typical of statically typed checked object oriented
这种很酷的C语言是非常典型的面向静态类型的检查对象
languages. But other families of languages will have different kinds of checks.
语言。但是其他语系会有不同种类的检查。